Guide to Oversized Materials Flat.File.Cases
New York University Archives
- Series III: Other University Buildings
  - Institute of Fine Arts (Uptown Manhattan, New York, NY), undated (Map-case 2, Drawer 20)
  - Institute of Fine Arts photograph, 1980ws (Map-case 6, Drawer 10)
  - Medical Center: Artist Renderings, undated (Map-case 4, Drawer 12)
  - Medical-Dental Center: Carnegie Building, Dental School (East River and 20th Street, New York, NY), undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 14)
  - Medical-Dental Center: Dental Center, undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 14)
  - Medical-Dental Center: Institute of Oral Hygiene (East River and 20th Street, New York, NY), undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 14)
  - Riverside Highrises: Artist Renderings, 1967 January 16 (Box 2)
  - Wall Street Center: Merrill Hall, Graduate School of Business Administration (100 Trinity Place, New York, NY), undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 12)
  - Wall Street Center: Nichols Hall, Graduate School of Business Administration (90 Trinity Place and Cedar Street, New York, NY), undated (Map-case 3, Drawer 12)
- Series IV: Certificates, Diplomas, and Proclamations
  - Subseries A: Awards and Certificates
    - Blank Certificates, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Blank Certificates: 25 Year Service Citation, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Blank Certificates: Certificate of Cooperation in Marshall Plan, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Blank Certificates: Charles Waldo Haskins Association, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Blank Certificates: College of Engineering Pre-Meteorology, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Blank Certificates: Hall of Fame, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Blank Certificates: Seminar for Executives in U.S. Securities, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Alumni Association Award of Distinction, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - American Field Service in France, Class of 1917 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Appointment of H. W. Chase to Mayor's Committee of New York City's Golden Jubilee, circa 1948 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Award Certificate for NYU and WCBS-TV Program, "Long Before Shakespeare", 1962 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Brown, Elmer E. (U.S. Commissioner of Education), Jun 23, 1906 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Certificate from U.S. Department of Defense in Honor of NYU Goliards, 1962 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Citations: Department of Hebrew and Judaic Studies, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Collins, G. Rowland, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Delta Zeta Sorority Affirmation, 1941 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Eta Mu Phi: Charter and Associated Documents, 1922 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Founder's Day Award, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Greetings of Metropolitan West Chapter to NYU College of Engineering, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Greetings to J. Hester on his Inauguration from the President of Rockefeller University, circa 1962 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Greetings to Other Universities: Blank, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Greetings to Other Universities: Catholic University of America, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Greetings to Other Universities: Tufts, 1976 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Institute of Education by Radio and Television: Award to Radio Department, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Mayoral Proclamation of NYU Week Oct 13-20, 1981, Oct 1981 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Men in Finance Award, Mar 31, 1959 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - NYU College Prize Certificate (8 copies to different high schools), 1893 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - NYU Service Citation (Blank), undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Paper Embossed with University Heights Campus, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Presidential Citation: Class of 1917, circa 1817 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Retirement Proclamation, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Service Citations (under Heald and other versions), undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Sprague, Chaplain Ezra: Military Decoration, May 5, 1891 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Testimonial for Charles Butler LL.D., undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - Violet Dedication, 1951 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
    - World's Fair, 1904: NYU Gold Medal Award, circa 1904 (Map-case 5, Drawer 12)
  - Subseries B: Diplomas
    - Blank Diploma: Graduate School of Business, 1966 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Blank Diploma: Sample, 1800s (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Blank Diploma: Sample, 1900s (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Blank Diploma: Sample Doctoral Degree, 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Blank Diploma: Sample Doctor of Medicine, 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Medical School diploma 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Dental School diploma Herman William Botein, 1893 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Blank Diploma: Sample Honorary Degree, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Blank Diploma: School of Engineering, 1967 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Engraving Plate of Bellevue Diploma, 1883 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Unidentified Diploma: Austria, 1831 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Unidentified Diploma: Parma, Italy, 1735 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Unidentified Diploma: Medical (I), 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Unidentified Diploma: Medical (II), 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Brown, Elmer Ellsworth: Honorary LL.D. (Doctor of Law), 1934 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Butler, Emily Ogden: Master of Arts (Literature, Humanities), 1902 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Drayton, Henry: LL. B. (Bachelor of Laws), 1861 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Drayton, Henry: Master of Arts, 1866 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Drayton, Henry S.: Legum Bacaleurae, 1861 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Dudek, Aliriam: M.Ph., 1896 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Dudet, Alice: Ph.D. and Business Card, 1899 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Edmondson, T.D.: Ph.D. (Clark University), 1896 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Francis, S. W.: Certificate, 1858 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Francis, S. W.: Certificate of Residency, 1862 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Francis, S.W.: Certificate of Resident Fellow [Fellowship], 1864 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Francis, S. W.: Diploma: Analytical and Practical Chemistry, 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Francis, S. W.: Doctor of Medicine, 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Francis, S. W.: Honorary Membership, New York Topographical Society, 1849 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Francis, S. W.: Medical Department Certificate of Hon. [Honor], 1859 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Francis, Samuel W: Doctor of Medicine, 1859-1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Gardiner, Gulielum: Bachelor of Arts, 1863 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Gardiner, W. H.: Doctor of Medicine, 1867 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Gatlin, Carolum Mortimer: Bachelor of Arts, 1848 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Gatlin, U.W. Stuyvesant: Bachelor of Arts, 1848 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Gillet, Professor W.K.: Doctor of Humanities (Huron College), 1913 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Greacen, Johannem: Bachelor of Arts, 1838 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Heath, Allen S.: Doctor of Medicine, 1844 (Map-case 5, Drawer 2)
    - Johnson, E.A.: Ph.D., 1862 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Megie, Burtis C.: Bachelor of Arts, 1835 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - McCallum, Samuel: M.D., 1879 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Millard, Charles W.: Bachelor of Arts, 1893 (Map-case 5, Drawer 4)
    - Rose, Alfredum: Bachelor of Arts, 1843 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Rose, Alfredum: Master of Arts, 1846 (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    - Stowell, D.P.: Doctor of Medicine, 1862 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Van Dyck, E. D.: Bachelor of Arts, 1880 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Van Dyck, E. D.: Master of Arts, 1883 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
    - Van Reypen, G. R.: Master of Arts, 1861 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Van Reypen, W. H.: Doctor of Medicine, 1862 (Map-case 5, Drawer 3)
    - Wood, R. A.: Bachelor of Science, 1915 (Map-case 5, Drawer 5)
- Series V: Images and Photographs
  - Unidentified Modern Building with World Trade Center in Background, circa 1973-2001 (Map-case 2, Drawer 15)
  - Artist's Impression of Loeb, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - Board of Trustees Photograph, circa 1995 (Box 1)
  - Building Photographs: Various, circa 1900s (Map-case 1, Drawer 1)
  - Chase, Chancellor Harry Woodburn, 1943 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Class of 1915: Photograph, circa 1915 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Class of 1931: 20th Reunion, May 26, 1951 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Close-up of Decorative Column Capitals (2), undated (Box 1)
  - Dunking Pond, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Engraving of NYU Building, 1850 (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - Engraving of NYU Building as Seen in Gleason's 1852, circa 1850s (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - Engraving of Washington Square Buildings, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - First Regiment Returns from Cuba, Lower 5th Avenue, circa 1899 (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - Frank H. Sommer (Law Alumni Association), 1942 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Hester, James (NYU President): Inauguration, circa 1962 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Historical Interiors and Exteriors: NYU Photo Bureau Prints (2), 1956 (Box 1)
  - Glee & Musical Club Members Portrait, 1921-1922 (Map-case 8, Drawer 7)
  - Glee Club and Hall of Fame Singers Portrait, 12 Dec. 1942 (Map-case 8, Drawer 7)
  - NYU Glee Club Concert: 23rd Annual Town Hall Concert, 1952 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Glee Club and Radcliffe Choral Society Portraits, 11 Dec. 1953 (Map-case 8, Folder 7)
  - Glee Club Camp Portrait, 1963 (Map-case 8, Drawer 7)
  - Glee Club Camp Portait, 1966 (Map-case 8, Drawer 7)
  - Glee Club Concert with Simon's College girls, 8 Dec. 1967 (Map-case 8, Drawer 7)
  - NYU Guide to University Locations, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - NYU Law School, Afternoon Division: Class of 1923, circa 1923 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Office of Radio and TV (In studio), circa 1955-1960 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Phi Gamma Delta Fraternity, 1913 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Photograph of NYU Building and Church, 1891 (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - Photographs of Buildings and Students, circa 1894-1980 (Map-case 1, Drawer 1)
  - Print of Painting of Military Parade Ground, 1851 (Map-case 5, Drawer 16)
  - Sawhill, John, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
    Original Location: Janice Gorn Papers (MC 98)
  - School of Commerce: Class Dinner, 1916 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - School of Commerce: Class of 1906, circa 1906 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - School of Commerce: Class of 1917: 10th Annual Reunion, 1927 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - School of Commerce: Class of 1915: First Annual Dinner, After 1915 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - School of Continuing Education: Adult Degree Studies Faculty, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Sniffen, D. Austin, ["President"], 1937-1939 (Map-case 5, Drawer 13)
  - Commerce, School of Class of 1906 (Box 7)
  - Law, School of Class of 1924 (Box 7)
  - Commerce, School of Class of 1917 10th Reunion 1927 (Box 7)
  - Baseball Team 1910 season (Box 7)
  - Baseball team 1914 season (Box 7)
  - Baseball team 1890s? (Box 7)
  - Football team, 1897 (Box 6)
  - Football team, 1910? (Box 6)
  - Football team, 1922 (Box 6)
  - Football team, 1920s? (Box 6)
  - Football team,1910? (Box 6)
  - Football team, 1904 (Box 6)
  - Glee Club Town Hall with Smith College, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Glee Club Town Hall, 1952 (Box 6)
  - First annual dinner Commerce Class of 1915 (Box 6)
  - Phi Gamma Delta Fraternity, 1920s? (Box 6)
  - Commerce class of 1916 class dinner in 1914 (Box 6)
- Series VI: Clippings, Graphic Materials, and Printed Matter
  - Announcement of Faculty and Courses, Oct 3, 1836 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Boston Weekly Messenger: Account of Founding NYU, Jun 8, 1837 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Daily News: Commencement Article, Jun 6, 1980 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Draper, John William: "First Photograph of a Human Face" [Portrait], 1840 (Map-case 5, Drawer 18)
  - Exhibition Materials: Anti-Vietnam 1968 (Map-case 6, Drawer 12)
    Original Location: "1968 Revisited" Exhibition (MC 132)
  - Flyer for Oratory of Heroes of 1876, Apr 12, 1875 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Geological Map of New Mexico and Colorado, 1881 (Map-case 5, Drawer 18)
  - Gleason's Pictorial: Description and Photograph of NYU, Sep 4, 1918 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Gleason's Pictorial: Photograph of NYU, Sep 4, 1852 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Golden Jubilee of Bronx County, Jan 19, 1964 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Governor's Citation for Exhibit on Mary Baker Eddy (Laminated Reproduction), 2004 (Box 1)
    Related Materials at the NYU Archives
    RG 12.25
  - Invitation to Meet Baron Rinfrew in Chapel, Oct 9, 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Leslie's Weekly: University Involvement in WWI Engineering and Machinery, Nov 12, 1918 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Map in German, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
    Original Location: Courant Papers (MC 150)
  - Map of Manhattan (New York, NY), 1831 (Map-case 1, Drawer 3)
  - Map of Northern Italy, circa 1800s (Box 2)
  - List of Occupants in University Building (Census of 1855), circa 1855 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - New York Daily Tribune: Description and Photo of NYU, Apr 15, 1894 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - New York Gazette, Jun 3, 1754 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - New York Herald: Summer School, Aug 18, 1907 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - New York Herald Tribune: Hall of Fame Ceremony, May 19, 1929 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - New York Herald Tribune: Photographs of Buildings to be Razed to Build Law School, Jun 9, 1932 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - New York Metropolitan Review, Apr 26, 1972 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - New York Mirror, Sep 13, 1834 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - New York Mirror: Description and Photo of NYU, Sep 13, 1934 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - New York Tribune [New York Times], Nov 7, 1870 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Alumni Reunion Weekend: Print Proof, 1991 (Box 2)
    Original Location: Records of the Office of External Affairs, Commencement, and Special Events (RG 7.4), Box 16, Folder 1.
  - NYU Daily News, Dec 23, 1925 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Daily News: 100th Anniversary Issue, 1931 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - NYU Historical Collection: Proof Sheets of Illustrations, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - NYU Incorporation Act, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Office of Undergraudate Admissions: Logo Envelope, undated
  - Palisades Handbook: Frosh Rules, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Pamphlet: "Within Bohemia's Borders: Greenwich Village, 1830-1930", 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - Program for 1915 Senior Production (Box 2)
  - Program for Tracey/Barry Gallery Exhibition: "You Make Me Feel [Mighty Real]: The Work of Robert Blanchon", 2009-2010 (Box 1)
    Related Materials at the New York University Archives
    Records of the NYU Libraries (Fales Library) (RG 38.6)
  - NYU Bonds: Coupon Sheets, circa 1937 (Box 1)
  - [The Richmond Whig], Apr 12, 1865 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Saturday Evening Post: Sunrise Semester, Apr 15, 1958 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Sawhill, John: Copy of State Law Initiated by, Jun 13, 1979 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Seals of the University, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Sheet Music: University Grand March, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Sheet Music: Funeral March for S. F. B. Morse, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Sheet Music: America Triumphant, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Sheet Music: A Prayer, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - The Tablet (Published by Psi Upsilon), Jan 15, 1860 (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Times Dispatch (Richmond, VA): Edgar Allen Poe, Jan 17, 1909 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - The University Item, undated (Map-case 5, Drawer 17, Drawer 9)
  - Variety: Clippings (2), Oct 22, 1990 and Nov 19, 1999 (Map-case 5, Drawer 18)
  - Variety: "NYU Film School Turns 60" (3 copies), Nov 19, 1999 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - Variety: "Tisch School Turns 25" (3 copies), Oct 22, 1990 (Map-case 5, Drawer 9)
  - The World Magazine: "Victory Hall, New York City's War Memorial", 1920 March 14 (Map-case 5, Drawer 18)
- Series VII: List of Collections for Separated Materials
  - Records of the Office of the Treasurer (Muriel L. Mantel) (R.G. 10.9) (Map-case 2, Drawer 18, Drawer 16, Drawer 17)
    Related Archival Materials note
    These oversized materials are part of the Records of the Office of the Treasurer (Muriel L. Mantel) (RG 10.9).
  - Records of the RISM Cross-Cultural Comparisons of Aging and Longevity Study (The Longevity Study) (RISM RG 15) (Map-case 4, Drawer 15)
    These oversized materials are part of the Records of the RISM Cross-Cultural Comparisons of Aging and Longevity Study, RISM RG 15.
  - John Brademas Congressional Papers (MC 168), circa 1970s (Map-case 4, Drawer 15, Drawer 10)
    These oversized materials are part of the John Brademas Congressional Papers, MC 168.
  - Oscar Falnes Papers (MC 135), 1911, 1916, 1918
    This oversized material is part of the Oscar Falnes Papers (MC 135) and was removed from Box 17. It consists of two diplomas and one item entitled "Roll of Honor, World's Great War for Democracy."
  - Flora Kaplan Papers (MC 300): Thomas Jekyll Exhibition Brochure (Map-case 2, Drawer 19)
    This brochure is part of the Flora Kaplan Papers, MC 300.
  - Nicholas Wahl Oversized Manuscript Collection (MC 147) (Map-case 5, Drawer 14)
    This oversized material is part of the Records of the French-American Foundation (MC 147).
  - Richard Courant Papers (MC 150) (Map-case 5, Drawer 1)
- Series VIII: Posters and Event Fliers
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 4, Drawer 6)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 4, Drawer 7)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 4, Drawer 8)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 4, Drawer 9)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 4, Drawer 10)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 5, Drawer 11)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 5, Drawer 15)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 5, Drawer 17)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Map-case 5, Drawer 18)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Box 3)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Box 4)
  - Posters and Event Fliers [See Access Database "Posters"] (Box 5)